# Nathan Johnson

Residence: 17129 N Larkspur Ln Surprise, AZ 85374

(507) 254-2279 nbjohnson@gmail.com

GitHub:

https://github.com/Elipticblock5

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nathan-johnson-467102179/

#### **Summary**

Experienced coding bootcamp graduate with extensive background in various coding languages, developing mobile applications, and building websites from the ground up. Specializes in JavaScript, and MERN stack technologies. Professional strengths include creative problem-solving, written and verbal communication, and time management. Detail-oriented mindset from 10+ years of experience in the insurance industry.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE University Of Arizona Software Engineering Immersive (Student), 2021

 Developed three mobile applications and built two user-friendly websites using full-stack Javascript and several other programming languages, libraries, and frameworks

#### Noted Projects:

- Created an interactive To-Do List app that helps users sort tasks into categories and then prioritize them into day, week, month schedules; used HTML, CSS, and JS React
- Developed a blog for current Arizona news and in-person events with user contributed content, dynamically updated weather information and custom login experience. Using Node, Express.js, HTML, CSS, and Handlebars.js

Claims Professional (Inside), Travelers Insurance, Boiler and Equipment Breakdown

Phoenix, AZ -- March 2019-present

- Handled first party and reinsurance claims from low to high complexity as assigned.
- Completed and administered investigations into claims to conclude facts of loss for proper coverage application and claim resolution.
- Negotiated claim settlements with insureds, public adjusters, and attorney-represented claims.
- Wrote timely and accurate coverage, denial, Reservation of Rights, and other claims correspondence letters.
- Maintained accurate diary and reserving of claim files.
- Met or exceeding claim handling best practices.
- Performed accurate and timely updates to internal, external, and reinsurance customers.
- Knowledgeable about various commercial and residential HVAC, boiler, electrical equipment, and mechanical equipment.
- Assigned and assisted managing own claims accounts.

# Property Field Claims Representative, Indiana Farm Bureau Insurance Indianapolis, IN -- October 2014-March 2019

- Provided fair, prompt and courteous claims service for 1st party property claims and third party liability claims for property damages.
  Followed and adhered to company guidelines and procedures.
- Worked closely with fellow property adjusters, SIU, and Unit Claims Coordinator to resolve coverage and indemnity issues.
- Adhered to all laws pertaining to claim settlements.
- Kept timely and accurate reserves and diaries for all claims assigned.
- Completed appraisals elevated potential serious claims to management for review.
- Maintained and recorded any problems with company issued equipment.

# Property Field Claims Adjuster, Hanover Insurance Group

Indianapolis, IN -- Jan 2013-Oct 2014.

Worked property claims both commercial and residential with exposures up to \$500.000. Determined insurance coverage, set exposures and reserves. Inspected, photographed, diagrammed and sketched damages for claim file. Wrote structure and personal property repair estimates. Responsible for writing all coverage correspondence for settlement letters, partial denials, and full denials, as well as, status and reservation of rights letters. Traversed roofs, attics, crawl spaces, basements, and other difficult access areas to document damages. Exceeded all performance standards for duties.

#### **Accomplishments**

- Certified Level 1 xactimate training
- Haag residential and commercial roof inspector certified.
- Implemented a new vendor program for steep and high roofs, water mitigation, and emergency services.
- Began AIC certification courses.
- Raised customer service score for area team by 35%

#### **Property Field Claims Adjuster, Farmers Insurance**

Burnsville, MN — Feb 2012-October 2012

Processed property insurance claims for nation's third largest insurance carrier. Determined insurance coverage then processed construction estimates and payments for customers. Accessed and inspected all areas of customer dwelling including attics, roofs, and crawl spaces to determine and establish causes of loss. Set reserves and inspected and photographed property damage. Set reserves and wrote denial, partial denial, reservation of rights, and settlement letters. Exceeded all quality and customer service goals set forth.

#### **Accomplishments**

- Exceeded all customer service goals with far exceeding expectation scores.
- Achieved far exceeds expectations scores on file quality and accuracy.

#### **Security Officer, Mayo Clinic**

Rochester, MN — 2003-2012

Responsible for coordinating security services and responses on large, culturally diverse, multi-state, and international medical campuses and universities.

Activities included responding and coordinating responses to medical, radiological, chemical, and criminal situations. Participated in the planning and execution of security operations for government facilities, State Department representatives, international clients, and foreign dignitaries. Proven ability to accomplish tasks while dealing with people under stressful and traumatic situations.

### Accomplishments

- Authored over 300 detailed incident reports used to minimize organizational liability and improve processes across all departments within the organization.
- Participated and led process improvement teams to better design responses to crisis situations which led to significant decreases in physical interventions.
- Achieved highest professional designation possible from International Association for Healthcare Security and Safety (IAHSS)

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **University of Arizona**

Certificate in Coding/Web Development -- 2021

#### Cardinal Stritch University (Rochester, MN)

Bachelors in Business Management — 2005-2008

## Phoenix/Scottsdale College (Phoenix, AZ)

Associates Degree in Honors Program Classics and Classical Studies -- 2001-2003

#### **REFERENCES**

- Stephany Prather
  - o Indiana Farm Bureau Insurance, Field Claim Rep
  - <u>(574) 967-4518</u>